Hello, my friends, and welcome again to the complete data structure and algorithms course.
In this video, we are going to solve exercise number 68, and we are asked to write a function that
adds nodes in the circle link of list at the end.
So you add in, you note at the end of that list, OK, we have seen how to make a method that is called
push.
We are adding the nodes at the beginning of the nodes, at the beginning of the list and make it as
the head.
So then you newly inserted node would be the head.
Here it is, the inverse.
We are adding new nodes in the circle link, at least at the end.
There is very important trick that the end of the circle and could list the end node will not refer
to then null as single link unless it were referred to the first one to the head.
OK, so pay attention for this.
Try to solve this exercise by your own self and based your code in the comments below.
In order to make discussion and if you have anything and any doubts, we can solve it and help you in
your problems.
OK, so we start by making public static.
It refers it is returning.
Type is known as we have seen in the push method where and at and OK, and we create a node called last
and end date and tick and data for the newly inserted note.
So we are adding a node that contains the data we are going to create its data and at the end node last
will be specifying last now.
So if
last equal, if we are to null, then we are going to return a method return last.
But we need to create this last.
So if we are adding this new node and the new node at or in empty list.
Then Note 10 equal to, you know, and temp dot data, equal to data, last equal to temp, assigning
the data and temp dot next equal to their last.
It's sort of ferreting itself.
OK, we link single note to itself.
This is by adding the new note in an empty list.
Now consider a list that contains data.
OK.
It is not an empty list.
It contains data adding note new notes in none.
Empty list.
OK.
We will create the note.
No stamp equal to new note.
OK.
And we assigned the data to it.
So attemptto data, I need to create a note and I add the data that at is best, but as parameter for
the function, add and add that end.
And I assigned the data to this step.
Now I need this is the data
data of created note and here the links link of create the Note 10 dot next.
Be equal to last the next last dot next equal to them.
And then this is that linkage of they're created.
And last thing, I need to make the last equal to the task.
OK.
We have created everything with them, and now I assign the note called Last that we have created passed
as parameter to return the last.
OK.
So how to make this newly created that note to be added at the end?
Let's see our function before to test it.
And here we have the contents of Circle Link list.
Now let's call our method.
We didn't call AB at the end.
OK.
OK, so we need to call it in the main method, so here have equal to because we need to add at the
end and at the end method returns the note I need to store it into a hat so had arrived at and I need
to push here or put here that had okay.
And I need to make here the number five.
OK, let's run and see how the this method works.
It adds it at the beginning because I have specified the head and at it at the beginning, OK, it was
at two.
Now let me make it had here called last node last equal to no.
I need to specify that.
I need to specify the last one.
OK, so last and I need to pass no one as last.
OK, I put last year it will be adding it at the end.
OK, so here we have the last.
Last year and that last.
Now, let's run and see.
It is added at the last one.
OK.
Because we have told that the last point or the last note contains one, I need to add number five after
that last, OK?
This is how we add the notes at the last at the end of that linked list.